Guide to the Frank Espada photographs and papers, 1946-2010 and undated, bulk 1975-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographic Prints Series, 1963-1991, (21 boxes)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New York: PROMESA, South Bronx, undated, (2 prints) (Box 45)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - New York: South Bronx (Box 46)
      - New York: PROMESA, South Bronx (Box 46)
      - Pennsylvania: Mushroom farm crew chief, Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 46)
      - Pennsylvania: Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 46)
      - Pennsylvania: Ricardo Molina, welding trainee, Lancaster, 1981 (Print 73) (Box 46)
      - Pennsylvania: Margarita at bilingual class, Reading, 1982 (Box 46)
      - Puerto Rico: Las Piedras, undated (Box 46)
      - Puerto Rico: Canary, 1981 (Box 46)
      - Puerto Rico: Juncos, 1981 (Box 46)
      - Washington DC: Hispanica Festival, 1983 (Box 46)
      - Washington DC: Hispanica Festival, 1982, (2 prints) (Box 46)
      - Wisconsin: Milwaukee, 1980 (Box 46)
    - Other projects
      - Chinese laundry, Blake Ave., East New York, 1964 (Box 46)
      - East New York, 1964 (Box 46)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - Long Island City, 1964 (Box 46)
      - School boycott, Brooklyn, 1964 (Box 46)
      - Mr. Jackson, Brooklyn, 1963 (Box 46)
  - 8x10 Box
    - Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project
      - Pennsylvania: Cook's boy, mushroom farm, Kennett Square, 1981 (Box 47)
      - Hawaii: Nancy Ortiz, OAHV, 1980 (Box 47)
      - Hawaii: Santa Rochiguez, Big Island, 1980 (Box 47)
      - New York: Tomas Hernandez, Williamsburg, Brooklyn, 1978 (Box 47)
      - New York: Miriam Colon, 1982 (Box 47)
    - Civil Rights Movement
      - Brooklyn, 1964, (11 prints) (Box 47)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      - Naputi family sitting on bench, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-1)
      - Nun and children (all children of ROTA), Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-2)
      - Children at desks, pretty girl leaning on desk, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-3)
      - Loling with her class at Guam U, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-4)
      - High school students in Guam (on steps), 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-5)
      - Senior citizens playing bridge, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-6)
      - Young woman with cap, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-7)
      - Politician with Panama hat and alligator shirt, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-8)
      - High school girls' group sitting on floor, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-9)
      - Poster girl (Stephanie), Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-10)
      - National Guard leader with sword, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-11)
      - Sweetheart couple sitting with feet in river, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-12)
      - Young boy with soda can, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-13)
      - Pretty little girl with bangs, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-14)
      - Four teenagers on couch outside house, Guam, 1990 (Box 48, Image CH-15)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      - Tour guide, Saipan, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-16)
      - Wood carver with bandana, Saipan, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-17)
      - Young people performing native dance, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-18)
      - Gay leader, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-19)
      - Man with flower shirt (son of dispossessed family, land taken by US Air Force), Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-20)
      - Mr. Naputi (fisherman), Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-21)
      - Young man with gold chain and amulet, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-22)
      - Two boys in friendly embrace, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-23)
      - Man with aviator glasses, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-24)
      - Young woman with class ring, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-25)
      - Classroom in ROTA, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-26)
      - Man with mustache and hand on face, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-27)
      - Young man with "DLN" and heart-shaped tattoo on arm, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-28)
      - Young woman with striped shirt playing ukulele, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-29)
      - Beautiful children of various backgrounds in story-telling class, Guam, 1990 (Box 49, Image CH-30)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      - Very old lady with big glasses (senior citizens' club), Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-31)
      - Beautiful child with puppy, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-32)
      - Brother and his sister--she has a Barbie necklace, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-33)
      - Girl receiving Loling's gold necklace as present--total surprise!, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-34)
      - Woman with big glasses and hand to chin, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-35)
      - Young man with crew cut, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-36)
      - Young kid sitting on stoop, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-37)
      - Young girl with hand on head, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-38)
      - Inside Chamorro grocery store, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-39)
      - Little kid looking at big hogs in pen, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-40)
      - Young woman in refuge house--cross earrings, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-42)
      - "I Love Justice" on way to Bordallo funeral march, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-43)
      - Young man with flag in Bordallo funeral march, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-44)
      - Farmer with cigarette--holding leaves, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-47)
      - Doctor examining patient at clinic, Guam, 1990 (Box 50, Image CH-49)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      - Woman in wheelchair, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-51)
      - Good-looking kid with Aloha shirt, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-52)
      - Japan Town, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-53)
      - Old man with big glasses, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-54)
      - Man with raised hand at political meeting, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-55)
      - Woman with five children at Bordallo funeral, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-62)
      - Little girl with ponytail, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-65)
      - Little girl standing at beach, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-66)
      - Little boy with sandals sitting on steps, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-67)
      - Future Guam representative (man), Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-71)
      - Man with glasses and Zapata mustache, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-73)
      - Mother cuddling her daughter (old lady in background), Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-77)
      - Girl leaning on concrete fence, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-80)
      - Woman sitting in park with indigenous totems, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-81)
      - Two young girl friends--with earrings, Guam, 1990 (Box 51, Image CH-82)
  - 11x14 Box
    - Chamorro Documentary Project
      - Building Japan Town, Guam, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-84)
      - Tailor cutting material, Saipan, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-94)
      - Loling and students in her classroom, Guam, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-101)
      - Four doctors standing in front of clinic (educated in US and returned to Guam), Guam, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-106)
      - Man in front of sign: "Guam's quest for commonwealth," Guam, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-107)
      - Young girl with striped blouse--loving look and bright smile, Guam, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-110)
      - Old lady laughing--covering her mouth (Senior Center), Guam, 1990 (Box 52, Image CH-111)
    - YES & Mission Agenda Projects
      - Blonde woman with hands on face--Star of David on right hand, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image Y-1)
      - Woman with dark hair and tear running down her face, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image Y-3)
      - Woman with long hair--holding her face, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image Y-4)
      - HIV Couple, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image Y-5)
      - Black man with curly hair and oxygen tube in his nose, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image Y-7)
      - Man with round glasses smoking cigarette, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image M-1)
      - Black man--bare chest, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image M-2)
      - Blonde woman talking into microphone--holding a rose to her head, San Francisco, 1990 (Box 52, Image M-3)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1979-1991 and undated, (2 boxes)
  The majority of this series consists of interview cassette tapes 1-129 (a total of 160 interviews) from the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project. There are also three videos of interviews with Espada.
  [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
  - Interviews, Frank Espada (Box 28)
    - Frank Espada interviews, WMHT 17 Arts Panorama, 1991 March 30 (VHS) (Box 28)
    - Frank Espada interview on Diaspora (BETA video cassette) (Box 28)
    - Frank Espada interview, Instruction video (VHS) (Box 28)
  - Interviews, Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project (Box 33)
    - 1: Jorge Piniero, Oakland, January 4, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 2: Western Council, Oakland, January 4, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 3: Blase Souza, Honolulu, January 10, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 4: Faith Evans, Honolulu, January 11, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 5: Solomon Vega, Kawai, January 14, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 6: Pablo Cardona, Milwaukee, WI, December 11, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 7: Angel Acevedo, Milwaukee, WI, December 11, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 8: Jose Hernandez, Milwuakee, WI, December 11, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 9: Spanish American Community, Cleveland, OH, December 13, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 10: Ricardo Fernandez, Cha Cha Jimenez, Chicago, IL, December 13, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 11: Rocky Ortiz, Lorrain, OH, December 14, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 12: Ramon Crespo, Jose Ortiz, Reading, PA, December 26, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 13: Carlos Ponce, Reading, PA, December 26, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 14: Ramon Crespo Sr., Reading, PA, December 26, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 15: Centro Hispano, Harrisburg, PA, December 26, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 16: Centro Hispano, Harrisburg, PA, December 26, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 17: Ed Roman/Seda, Lancaster, PA, December 28, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 18: Ramon Santiago/El Centro, Lancaster, PA, December 18, 1979 (Box 33)
    - 19: PROMESA, So. Bronx, NY, January 9, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 20: (A) Mike Laguna/Crossroads, New Haven, CT, January 29, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 20: (B) Gumercindo del Rio/JUNTO, New Haven, CT, January 29, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 21: (A) Gabriel Cabrera/JUNTO, New Haven, CT, January 29, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 21: (B) Menen Osorio, New Haven, CT, January 30, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 22: Edith & Melvin Colon/Burgos Ctr., Hartford, CT, January 30, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 23: (A) Armengol Domenech/Burgos Ctr., Hartford, CT, January 30, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 23: (B) Tony Soto/La Casa, Hartford, CT, January 31, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 24: Nelson Dawes, Hartford, CT, January 31, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 25: Calixtro Torres/CAMINEMOS, Hartford, CT, February 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 26: Antonio Gonzalez/City Hall, Hartford, CT, February 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 27: Luis Rodriguez/IBA, Boston, MA, February 19, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 28: Nick Arana/CONCILIO, Boston, MA, February 19, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 29: (A) Gladys Rodriguez, Boston, MA, February 20, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 29: (B) Ana Hernandez Perez/ALIANZA, Boston, MA, February 21, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 30: (A) Raquel Ortiz/LA PLAZA/WGPH, Boston, MA, February 21, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 30: (B) Inez Stewart/PR COMMONWEALTH, Boston, MA, February 21, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 31: Gil Valdiris, Gregorio Rivera, Jose Delgado, AREYTO, Boston, MA, February 21, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 32: Oscar Alers/MIGRATION CONSORTIUM, New York City, March 7, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 33: Manny Diaz Jr., New York City, March 20, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 34: Jack Agueros/Museo del Bario, New York City, March 20, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 35: Robert Roriguez, Councilman, New York City, March 21, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 36: Evelina Antonetti/UNITED BRONX PARENTS, Bronx, NY, March 21, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 37: Angel Dominguez/CATA, Vineland, NJ, April 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 38: (A) Tommy Rodriguez, Vineland, NJ, April 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 38: (B) Alfonso Roman/CONGRESO de NJ, Trenton, NJ, April 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 39: Alfonso Roman/CONGRESO de NJ, Trenton, NJ, April 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 40: Miguel Torres, Jersey City, NJ, April 3, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 41: (A) Jose Rosario/FOCUS, Newark, NJ, April 3, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 41: (B) Eliu Rivera/PACO, Jersey City, NJ, April 3, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 42: Miriam Colon/PR TRAVELING THEATRE, New York City, January 1, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 43: Jose Acuna/Manhattan Valley Development, New York City, January 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 44: Johnny Colon/East Harlem Music School, New York City, January 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 45: Boricua College students, New York City, January 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 46: Robert Torres, Las Piedras, PR, February 26, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 47: Students at Ramon Power High School, Las Piedras, PR, February 26, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 48: Jose Figueroa, Las Piedras, PR, February 26, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 49: Rosa Santos, Urb Country Club, PR, February 28, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 50: Avelino & Wilma Reyes, Rio Piedras, PR, March 4, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 51: Peter Rios and family, Santurce, PR, April 5, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 52: (A) Maria & Juan Hernandez, Las Piedras, PR, March 7, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 52: (B) Ismael & Ana Aponte, Las Piedras, PR, March 7, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 53: (A) Ada Castro, Juncos, PR, March 7, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 53: (B) Janet & Orlando Encarnacion, Juncos, PR, March 7, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 54: Shinka House Residents, Oahu, HI, March 30, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 55: Rodney and Ann Morales, Oahu, HI, April 2, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 56: John Vegas, Kalihi Valley, Honolulu, HI, April 3, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 57: Tana & Ralph Rios, Kalihi Valley, Honolulu, HI, April 3, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 58: Young People in Oahu, Honolulu, HI, April 4, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 59: Johnny & Julia Matias, Honolulu, HI, April 5, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 60: Joe Velez, Kapala, HI, April 6, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 61: Confessor Riveria & Tony Diaz, Kona, HI, April 6, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 62: Confessor Riveria & Tony Diaz, Kona, HI, April 6, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 63: At Confessor's Riveira's house, Kona, HI, April 8, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 64: At Confessor Riveira's house, Kona, HI, April 8, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 65: Santos Caravalho, Hilo, HI, April 10, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 66: Carmen Rodriguez, NYC, March 18, 1980 (Box 33)
    - 67: Jaime Rodriguez & Rafael Diaz, Las Piedras, PR, February 27, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 68: Tony Collazo, Los Angeles, CA, April 19, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 69: David Santiago, Los Angeles, CA, April 19, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 70: Eddie Batis, Los Angeles, April 20, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 71: Sonny Aguizoni, East Los Angeles, CA, April 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 72: Tommy Cheveres, Los Angeles, CA, April 28, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 73: Lila Calderon De Romero, San Leandro, CA, April 29, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 74: Edelmiro Huertas, San Francisco, CA, May 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 75: Eddie Rivera, San Francisco, CA, May 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 76: Moises Rodriguez, Hayward, CA, May 2, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 77: Young People/CENTRO DE VIDA, Harrisburg, PA, May 27, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 78: Angel Luis Jimenez, Reading, PA, May 28, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 79: ESL Program- Basic, Harrisburg, PA, May 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 80: Manuel y Sandra Molina, Kennet Square, PA, May 29, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 81: Margarita Quinones, Kennet Square, PA, May 29, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 82: Mushroom Workers: Marcelino Martinez & Ped Lopez, Kennett Square, PA, June 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 83: (A) Ricardo Molina, Lancaster, PA, June 2, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 83: (B) Edgardo Exia, Clara Carrion, Lancaster, PA, June 2, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 84: Angel Luis Pereira, Adela Valentin, Lancaster, PA, June 2, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 85: Raquel Yiengst, Bilingual Program Director, Reading, PA, June 4, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 86: Angie Echevarria, Los Angeles, CA, April 19, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 87: Margarita Morales Kerns, ESL Program, Harrisburg, PA, May 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 88: Cesar Perales, New York City, June 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 89: Doris Moises/PROMESA, So. Bronx, NY, November 11, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 90: Ismael Bentencourt at Plant, So. Bronx, NY, June 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 91: Ismael Bentencourt at LaGallera, So. Bronx, NY, June 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 92: (A) Jose Acuna, Manhattan Valley, NYC, June 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 92: (B) Pacheco-Baez Family, Manhattan Valley, NYC, June 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 93: Willie Vazquez, Washington, DC, August 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 94: Eugenio Caro, Hartford, CT, October 19, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 95: Eugenio Caro, Hartford, CT, October 19, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 96: Robert Laboy, Hartford, CT, October 21, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 97: Max Fernandez, Hartford, CT, October 21, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 98: Maria Sanchez & Maria Serrano, Hartford, CT, October 21, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 99: Edna Negron, Hartford, CT, October 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 100: Mildred Torres, Hartford, CT, October 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 101: Housing Meeting, Hartford, CT, October 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 102: Maria Borrero, Hartford, CT, October 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 103: Tony Soto, Hartford, CT, October 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 104: Tony Soto, Hartford, CT, October 22, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 105: Alberto Garcia, Bronx, NY, November 1, 1981 (Box 33)
    - 106: Juan Gonzalez, Philadelphia, PA, February 11, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 107: Juan Gonzalez, Philadelphia, PA, February 11, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 108: Samuel Betances, Chicago, IL, February 14, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 109: Samuel Betances, Chicago, IL, February 14, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 110: Angel Dominguez, Glassboro, NJ, May 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 111: Petra Gonzales, Penn's Grove, NJ, May 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 112: Juan Ortiz, Vineland, NJ, May 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 113: Pedro Caravallo, Vineland, NJ, May 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 114: CATA meeting, Vineland, NJ, May 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 115: Lenny Durio, Hartford, CT, June 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 116: At Cookie's House, Hartford, CT, June 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 117: Centro san Lazaro/Marta de Jesus, Hartford, CT, June 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 118: Marta Jimenez, Chicago, IL, August 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 119: Tommy & Angel Jimenez, Chicago, IL, August 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 120: Richard Gonzalez, Chicago, IL, August 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 121: Collazo Family, Chicago, IL, August 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 122: Carlos Aulet, Chicago, IL, August 1, 1982 (Box 33)
    - 123: George & Carmen Caraballo, Maui, HI, February 1, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 124: Solomon Vega & Maria Espinoza, Oahu, HI, February 1, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 125: Tony Baez, Milwaukee, WI, May 1, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 126: Tony Baez, Milwaukee, WI, May 1, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 127: Luis & Pablo Baez, Milwaukee, WI, May 1, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 128: Pedro Cruz & Cesar Pabon, Milwaukee, WI, May 1, 1983 (Box 33)
    - 129: Israel Acosta & Tony Gonzalez, Milwaukee, WI, May 1, 1983 (Box 33)
- Oversize Materials, 1958-2008, (2 folders)
  Oversize manuscript materials, including proclamations, essays or writings by Espada, and certificates from Espada's photography courses.
  - Faces of the Sixties introduction, 1988 (signed) (Opaperfolder 1)
  - YES Outreach Program to Combat AIDS introduction, 1991 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - New York Institute of Photography certificate for Commercial Photography graduation, February 1958 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - New York Institute of Photography certificate for Portrait Photography graduation, June 1958 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - New York Institute of Photography merit award for Portraiture, September 1958 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Honorary Doctor of Arts degree, Herbert H. Lehman College, 2008 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Village Camera Club Outstanding Photographic Achievement certificate, January 1960 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Puerto Rican Community Day, formal Boston Proclamation, December 1985 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Posters and other promotional material from Espada's exhibits, particularly from the Puerto Rican Diaspora Documentary Project (Opaperfolder 2)